{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "Physical Science",
    "Term": "First Quarter",
    "Title": "Phisical Science Reviewer Pro Max",
    "LastModified": "15 August 2025",
    "Authors": [
      "Alexander Oro"
    ],
    "References": [
      "1.2.Formation-of-Elements.pdf",
      "BIG-BANG-THEORY.pdf",
      "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf"
    ]
  },
  "quizData": [
    {
      "question": "What is the process that creates new atomic nucleus from pre-existing nucleons, which is protons and neutrons?",
      "answer": "Nucleosynthesis",
      "choices": [
        "Stellar Nucleosynthesis",
        "Big Bang Nucleosynthesis",
        "Nuclear Fusion",
        "Nucleosynthesis"
      ],
      "reference": "1.2.Formation-of-Elements.pdf",
      "term": "Nucleosynthesis"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the production of the \"light elements\" shortly after Big Bang?",
      "answer": "Primordial (Big Bang Nucleosynthesis)",
      "choices": [
        "Stellar Nucleosynthesis",
        "Primordial (Big Bang Nucleosynthesis)",
        "Nuclear Fusion",
        "Supernova"
      ],
      "reference": "1.2.Formation-of-Elements.pdf",
      "term": "Nucleosynthesis"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the process by which light nuclei fuse together to form a heavier nucleus?",
      "answer": "Nuclear Fusion",
      "choices": [
        "Stellar Nucleosynthesis",
        "Big Bang Nucleosynthesis",
        "Nuclear Fusion",
        "Nucleosynthesis"
      ],
      "reference": "1.2.Formation-of-Elements.pdf",
      "term": "Fundamental Processes"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a form of an element that has the same atomic number of the original element but with different atomic mass or mass number?",
      "answer": "Isotopes",
      "choices": [
        "Protons",
        "Neutrons",
        "Isotopes",
        "Nucleons"
      ],
      "reference": "1.2.Formation-of-Elements.pdf",
      "term": "Atomic Structure"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the formation of heavy elements by fusion of lighter nuclei in the interior of star called?",
      "answer": "Stellar Nucleosynthesis",
      "choices": [
        "Stellar Nucleosynthesis",
        "Big Bang Nucleosynthesis",
        "Nuclear Fusion",
        "Supernova"
      ],
      "reference": "1.2.Formation-of-Elements.pdf",
      "term": "Nucleosynthesis"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a massive explosion of a star?",
      "answer": "Supernova",
      "choices": [
        "Red Giant",
        "Supernova Remnant",
        "Neutron Capture",
        "Supernova"
      ],
      "reference": "1.2.Formation-of-Elements.pdf",
      "term": "Stellar Evolution"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the structure resulting from the explosion of a star in a supernova?",
      "answer": "Supernova Remnant (SNR)",
      "choices": [
        "Supernova",
        "Red Giant",
        "Supernova Remnant (SNR)",
        "Neutron Capture"
      ],
      "reference": "1.2.Formation-of-Elements.pdf",
      "term": "Stellar Evolution"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the branch of astronomy that involves the origin and evolution of the universe?",
      "answer": "Cosmology",
      "choices": [
        "Astronomy",
        "Big Bang Theory",
        "Cosmology",
        "Nucleosynthesis"
      ],
      "reference": "BIG-BANG-THEORY.pdf",
      "term": "Cosmology"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is a scientist who uses space-based and ground-based telescope and satellites to study the properties of the universe?",
      "answer": "Cosmologist",
      "choices": [
        "Astronomer",
        "Scientist",
        "Cosmologist",
        "Physicist"
      ],
      "reference": "BIG-BANG-THEORY.pdf",
      "term": "Cosmology"
    },
    {
      "question": "What theory explains how the elements were initially formed?",
      "answer": "Big Bang Theory",
      "choices": [
        "Nucleosynthesis",
        "Big Bang Theory",
        "Singularity",
        "Inflation"
      ],
      "reference": "BIG-BANG-THEORY.pdf",
      "term": "Theories of Origin"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a point of space or a moment in the time where the universe was infinitely hot and dense?",
      "answer": "Singularity",
      "choices": [
        "Inflation",
        "Singularity",
        "Recombination",
        "Annihilation"
      ],
      "reference": "BIG-BANG-THEORY.pdf",
      "term": "Stages of the Big Bang"
    },
    {
      "question": "What refers to the epoch at which charged electrons and protons first became bound to form electrically neutral hydrogen atom?",
      "answer": "Recombination",
      "choices": [
        "Inflation",
        "Annihilation",
        "Recombination",
        "Nucleosynthesis"
      ],
      "reference": "BIG-BANG-THEORY.pdf",
      "term": "Stages of the Big Bang"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a theory of exponential expansion of space in the early universe?",
      "answer": "Inflation",
      "choices": [
        "Red Shift",
        "Inflation",
        "Big Bang Theory",
        "Singularity"
      ],
      "reference": "BIG-BANG-THEORY.pdf",
      "term": "Stages of the Big Bang"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the reaction in which a particle and its antiparticle collide and disappear, releasing energy?",
      "answer": "Annihilation",
      "choices": [
        "Recombination",
        "Annihilation",
        "Fusion",
        "Fission"
      ],
      "reference": "BIG-BANG-THEORY.pdf",
      "term": "Key Concepts"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the displacement of spectral lines toward longer wavelengths in radiation from distant galaxies and celestial objects?",
      "answer": "Red Shift",
      "choices": [
        "Cosmic Microwave Background",
        "Red Shift",
        "Inflation",
        "Annihilation"
      ],
      "reference": "BIG-BANG-THEORY.pdf",
      "term": "Key Concepts"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the basic unit of all matter and chemical element?",
      "answer": "Atoms",
      "choices": [
        "Nucleus",
        "Atoms",
        "Protons",
        "Electrons"
      ],
      "reference": "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "term": "Atomic Theory"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the centre of the atom?",
      "answer": "Nucleus",
      "choices": [
        "Shells",
        "Nucleus",
        "Orbits",
        "Protons"
      ],
      "reference": "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "term": "Atomic Structure"
    },
    {
      "question": "Where is all of the mass of the atom contained?",
      "answer": "Nucleus",
      "choices": [
        "Orbits",
        "Shells",
        "Nucleus",
        "Electrons"
      ],
      "reference": "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "term": "Atomic Structure"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the positively charged particles which are present in the nucleus of the atom?",
      "answer": "Protons",
      "choices": [
        "Electrons",
        "Neutrons",
        "Protons",
        "Nucleus"
      ],
      "reference": "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "term": "Subatomic Particles"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the neutral particles which are present in the nucleus of an atom?",
      "answer": "Neutrons",
      "choices": [
        "Electrons",
        "Neutrons",
        "Protons",
        "Nucleus"
      ],
      "reference": "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "term": "Subatomic Particles"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the negatively charged particles which are present in the outer orbits surrounding the nucleus of an atom?",
      "answer": "Electrons",
      "choices": [
        "Electrons",
        "Neutrons",
        "Protons",
        "Shells"
      ],
      "reference": "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "term": "Subatomic Particles"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who discovered the positively charge subatomic as a component of annode rays in 1886?",
      "answer": "Eugene Goldstein",
      "choices": [
        "J.J. Thomson",
        "James Chadwick",
        "Eugene Goldstein",
        "Ernest Rutherford"
      ],
      "reference": "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "term": "History of Discovery"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who coined the term proton for positively charged particle in an atom (1917-1920)?",
      "answer": "Ernest Rutherford",
      "choices": [
        "J.J. Thomson",
        "Eugene Goldstein",
        "Ernest Rutherford",
        "James Chadwick"
      ],
      "reference": "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "term": "History of Discovery"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who discovered the neutral particles, which he called neutrons, in the nucleus of an atom in 1932?",
      "answer": "James Chadwick",
      "choices": [
        "James Chadwick",
        "J.J. Thomson",
        "Eugene Goldstein",
        "Ernest Rutherford"
      ],
      "reference": "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "term": "History of Discovery"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who discovered that an atom is also composed of negatively charged particles which was named electrons in 1897?",
      "answer": "J.J. Thomson",
      "choices": [
        "J.J. Thomson",
        "James Chadwick",
        "Eugene Goldstein",
        "Ernest Rutherford"
      ],
      "reference": "PARTS-OF-ATOMS.pdf",
      "term": "History of Discovery"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who first introduced the idea of the atom?",
      "answer": "Leucippus and Democritus",
      "choices": [
        "Aristotle",
        "Dalton",
        "Leucippus and Democritus",
        "Thomson"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "Early Atomic Theory"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who believed that there was a limit to how far matter could be broken down into smaller pieces?",
      "answer": "Leucippus",
      "choices": [
        "Democritus",
        "Leucippus",
        "Aristotle",
        "Dalton"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "Early Atomic Theory"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who gave the smallest component of matter the name \"atomos\"?",
      "answer": "Democritus",
      "choices": [
        "Leucippus",
        "Democritus",
        "Aristotle",
        "Dalton"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "Early Atomic Theory"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who believed that the world was made of earth, air, fire, and water?",
      "answer": "Aristotle",
      "choices": [
        "Democritus",
        "Leucippus",
        "Aristotle",
        "Dalton"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "Early Atomic Theory"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the father of modern chemistry?",
      "answer": "Antoine-Laurent Lavoisier",
      "choices": [
        "Robert Boyle",
        "Antoine-Laurent Lavoisier",
        "John Dalton",
        "J.J. Thomson"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "19th Century Models"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the earliest practices of chemical science?",
      "answer": "Alchemy",
      "choices": [
        "Chemistry",
        "Science",
        "Alchemy",
        "Mythology"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "Early Chemistry"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who published \"The Skeptical Chymist\" in 1661?",
      "answer": "Robert Boyle",
      "choices": [
        "Antoine-Laurent Lavoisier",
        "Robert Boyle",
        "John Dalton",
        "J.J. Thomson"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "19th Century Models"
    },
    {
      "question": "What theory states that all matter is made up of atoms- extremely minute, indestructible, and indivisible particle?",
      "answer": "Dalton's Atomic Theory",
      "choices": [
        "Thomson Atomic Theory",
        "Dalton's Atomic Theory",
        "Rutherford's Model of Atom",
        "Modern Atomic Theory"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "19th Century Models"
    },
    {
      "question": "What theory states that atoms can neither be created nor destroyed?",
      "answer": "Dalton's Atomic Theory",
      "choices": [
        "Thomson Atomic Theory",
        "Dalton's Atomic Theory",
        "Rutherford's Model of Atom",
        "Modern Atomic Theory"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "19th Century Models"
    },
    {
      "question": "What model of the atom is also known as the nuclear model?",
      "answer": "Rutherford's Model of Atom",
      "choices": [
        "Dalton's Atomic Model",
        "Thomson Atomic Theory",
        "Rutherford's Model of Atom",
        "Plum Pudding Model"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "19th Century Models"
    },
    {
      "question": "What model proposes that an atom has a small, dense, positively charged nucleus at its center, with electrons orbiting this nucleus?",
      "answer": "Rutherford's Model of Atom",
      "choices": [
        "Dalton's Atomic Model",
        "Thomson Atomic Theory",
        "Rutherford's Model of Atom",
        "Plum Pudding Model"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "19th Century Models"
    }
  ]
}